U.S. Anthracite Coal Commission Publications 5389
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Anthracite Coal Commission Publications
1920-1923
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
United States Anthracite Coal Commission
5389
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection consists of publications either produced by the Commission or submitted to the Commission.
3338498
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 24, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5502 mf: John Mitchell Papers on Microfilm 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1 5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2 5619: ACWA Records 5897 mf: Strike Files of the U.S. Department of Justice, Pt. 1 on Microfilm 5956: Archives Organization File Additional records 6034: Rare Pamphlet Collection 6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
Bituminous Coal Producers Board (U.S.); United States Anthracite Coal Commission; United States. Coal Commission.; United States. National Bituminous Coal Commission
3338498
- A, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "A"
  - Item 1: Accounting and Finance, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By United Mine Workers of America. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Anthracite Coal Strike of 1922, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By General Policies Committee of Anthracite Operators. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The Antracite Emergency of 1922-1923 and How It Was Handled, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: The Anthracite Monopoly Anthracite, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
- B, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "B"
  - Item 1: Statement of J. C. Brydon, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By J. C. Brydon. Item is in English.
- C, 1920-1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "C"
  - Item 1: The Case of the Anthracite Coal Mine Workers, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Philip Murray. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Central Pennsylvania Coal Producers' Association and the Association of Bituminous Coal Operators of Central Pennsylvania Brief, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Central Pennsylvania Coal Producers' Association; Association of Bituminous Coal Operators of Central Pennsylvania. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The Central Pennsylvania Coal Producers' Association and the Association of Bituminous Coal Operators of Central Pennsylvania Brief, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Central Pennsylvania Coal Producers' Association; Association of Bituminous Coal Operators of Central Pennsylvania. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Coal Controversy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America. Bulletin no.2 (1922:May). Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Combination in the Anthracite Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By W. Jett Lauck. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Company Town, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Bituminous Operators' Special Committee. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Company Town, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Bituminous Operators' Special Committee. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Comparison of Earnings and Wage Rates in the Anthracite and Bituminous Mines of Pennsylvania, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: Comparison of Wages of Bituminous Miners With Wages of Employes in Other Industries, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: Competition in the Anthracite Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Gerenal Policies Committee of Anthracite Operators. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Constructive Action As To Labor Relations in the Coal Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
- E, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "E"
  - Item 1: Economics, Accounting, and the Constitution in the Coal Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
- F, 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "F"
  - Item 1: Freight Rates on Anthracite Coal 1914-1920, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Freight Rates On Anthracite Coal 1914-1920, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By W. Jett Lauck. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- I, 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "I"
  - Item 1: Irregularity of Employment in the Anthracite Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Irregularity of Employment in the Anthracite Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- K, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "K"
  - Item 1: Kanawha Coal Operators' Association's Statement to the Commission, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Kanawha Coal Operators' Association. Item is in English.
- L, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "L"
  - Item 1: Labor Relations in the Anthracite Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Henry S. Denison; Willard E. Hotchkiss; Joseph H. Willits. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Letter and Memorandum of Bituminous Operators' Special Committee on Methods of Determining Rate of Profit in the Bituminous Coal Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: Letter and Statement to the United States Coal Commission on Herrin, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Letter to the United States Coal Commission Suggesting a Method of Analyzing the Data as to Cost and Realization, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
- M, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "M"
  - Item 1: Memorandum on the Proper Treatment of Coal Reserves in Determing the Fair Present Value of Mining Properties, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: Memorandum on the Treatment of Income and Excess Profits Taxes in Determining Margin of Profit, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
- N, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "N"
  - Item 1: Need for Greater Democracy in the Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
- O, 1920-1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "O"
  - Item 1: Occupation Hazard of Anthracite Miners, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 2: Operating and Financial Performance of Anthracite Railroads, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 3: Operating and Financial Performance of Anthracite Railroads, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 4: Outlaw Strikes in the Anthracite Fields, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
- P, 1920-1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "P"
  - Item 1: Profits of Anthracite Operators, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: Profits of Anthracite Operators, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Proposed Findings As To Certain Aspects of the Bituminous Coal Mining Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By Bituminous Operators's Special Committee. Item is in English.
- R, 1920-1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "R"
  - Item 1: The Relations Between Wages and Production, Cost, Prices, and Profits in the Anthracite Mining Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 2: The Relations Between Wages and Production, Costs, Prices, and Profits in the Anthracite Mining Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: The Relationship Between Rates of Pay and Earnings and the Cost of Living in the Anthracite Industry of Pennsylvania, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 4: Reply of the Anthracite Operators to the Demands of the Anthracite Mine Workers, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By S. D. Warriner; W. J. Richards; C. F. Huber. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Relpy of the Bituminous Operators' Special Committee, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 6: Report of United States Coal Commission on Anthracite, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By United States Coal Commission. July 9, 1923. Reprinted from Coal Age. Item is in English.
- S, 1920-1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "S"
  - Item 1: The Sanction for a Living Wage, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 2: The Sanction for the Eight-Hour Day, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 3: The Sanction for the Eight-Hour Day, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 4: The Soft Coal Controversy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By W. Jett Lauck; T. H. Watkins. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Statement As to the "Check-Off", Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 6: Statement to the Commission by the Somerset County Coal Operators' Association, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Somerset County Coal Operators' Association. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Statement to the United States Coal Commission by the Southern Appalachian Coal Operators' Association, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Southern Appalachian Coal Operators' Association. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Statement to the United States Coal Commission by the Southern Wyoming Coal Operators' Association, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Southern Wyoming Coal Operators' Association. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Statement to the United States Coal Commission by the Southwestern Interstate Coal Operators' Association, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Southwestern Interstate Coal Operators' Association. Missouri, Kansas, Arkansas, and Oklahoma. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Statement to the United States Coal Commission on Coal Transportation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 11: Summary and Recommendations As to Industrial Relations In the Anthracite Fields, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 12: Summary of the Oral Argument Before the United States Coal Commission, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Bituminous Coal Operators' Special Committee. Item is in English.
- T, 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "T"
  - Item 1: The Trade Union As the Basis for Collective Bargaining, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
- U, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "U"
  - Item 1: Union Mine Labor in Illinois and the Determination of Wage Scales and Working Conditions, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By Illinois Coal Operators. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The United Mine Workers in West Virginia, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 3: The United Mine Workers in West Virginia, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 4: The Unied Mine Workers in West Virginia, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By Bituminous Operators' Special Committee. Copy 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Union Rules and Practices: Limiting Output and Impairing Efficiency in the Anthracite Fields, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 6: The Union Ultimatum: The Check-Off or No Anthracite, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 7: The Union Ultimatum: The Check-Off or No Anthracite, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By General Policies Committee of Anthracite Operators. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- V, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "V"
  - Item 1: Violence in the Coal Fields, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Bituminous Operators' Special Committee. A series of news releases sumarizing briefs filed with United States Coal Commission by Councel for Bituminous Operators' Special Committee or co-operating organizations. Item is in English.
- W, 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Publications submitted to the Commission: titles beginning with letter "W"
  - Item 1: Wholesale and Retail Prices of Anthracite Coal 1913-1920, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)